Morning.
Questions?
Uh have you made a decision what you're
doing with with Mono here for the last
game?
I don't see playing him this last one.
Was he
close?
Oh, yeah. I'd say yeah, he was better,
you know.
Just trying to get his legs back under
him.
Was there any value in getting him for
these last three or four weeks in
practice to to I guess catapult him into
2026? Well, it's certainly not going to
hurt, you know, you get football reps
and so those have been good for him. I
mean, he looks a lot better than he did,
you know, 3 weeks ago when he started.
So, that's that's that's a good thing,
you know, he gets some individual work,
some technique work, team work against
our defense. So, that's that always
helps.
What about Amon-Ra St. Brown?
Uh he he uh he's trending the right way
right now. We'll see, you know, he's
going to try to go out there a little
bit today
and run around and uh and and we'll see.
Dan, in 2022 you guys came into the last
game of the season with same eight and
eight record. Obviously, different
circumstances. What's the difference in
the mindset of the players you think
from when eight and eight going into
Green Bay with a chance to get one in
and now this year eight and eight with
no chance? Well, I I think more than
anything the focus is just we got one
more, you know, this is it, man. Like
today's our last Friday practice. We're
going outside, it's snowing out there.
Let's go.
Right? And let's get the work in. Let's
make it good. Let's make it crisp. Um
and we got one game. All you got, man.
All you got and you can load your car up
and go wherever you need to go and do
whatever you need to do and we'll
regroup and get ready for next year. But
right now, all you got, man, for one
game.
Have you been able to to pinpoint, you
know, where things went wrong or why? I
mean, a lot of us point to like Ragnow
leaving and the the trickle down that
had on the offensive line. I don't know
if there's one
Yeah, I'm not Look, there there's always
as with everything when it doesn't work
the way that uh
that we want it to work, it's number of
things, you know, there's there's a lot
of things that go into it and do I have
a couple of ideas maybe right now, but I
I need some time here. I need I need
time um to really sit down and
and think about all this, you know, um
but what we do know is one way or
another probably change is inevitable,
you know. Now, it may not be much, but
there will be something that'll change.
You mentioned back in LA after that game
of
some of the young guys on this roster
really having experience through a game
situation like this where
nothing to play for, if you will.
What what do you hope they take away
from
this experience, I guess, this last
week? Uh you talking about the young
guys?
>> first second year guys who haven't Well,
they are playing for a lot. So,
they are, you know, and uh
>> [snorts]
>> you know, I've asked this the last 2
years. I've sat up there with different
players that got an opportunity and I
said,
"Did you did you give everything you had
cuz you had an opportunity to play?"
They played on the last game of the
year.
And knowing that, knowing that this
probably is your last game, did you give
everything you had? Was was all your
focus in it? Or was it really?
Cuz there's no guarantee that you're
going to get a chance to play again or
start again. You're just not. Every
year's different, you know.
There's very few players you can say,
"You know what?
That guy I know is going to start next
year."
You know.
I mean, I think you'd be
Penei Sewell's probably going to start,
right? I mean, yeah, we know that. But
but it it doesn't go that way with
everybody, you know, we're going to have
to
we're going to reload and uh go back to
the basics of some of the things we do
and get back to what we were in '21 and
'22 a little bit.
Kalif said a uptick in target share over
the last 2 weeks. He's got four
touchdowns in his last five games. What
do you what do you like about the way
he's ending the season and and what do
you think has caused him to Who's that?
I'm sorry.
>> Kalif. Just now. Yeah, you know, he he's
done a
he's done a really good job and
you know, I would say he's he's probably
grown more than anybody has uh
throughout the year as far as our young
guys. He's grown the most. Um you know,
just
and and what you love about him is is is
why he's here. Um
Of course, he's got ability, but man,
he's smart. He's instinctive. He's
tough. He's a finisher.
Uh he's resilient, you know, every week
we've been able to put more and more on
him, you know, he's serving a lot of
different roles, playing a lot of
different positions, but
he's just continued to
um you know, he's one of those guys that
um that broke through probably that
rookie wall at at some point and just
kept going, you know, and uh that's
that's what you want. Those are the guys
you're looking for. Okay, kind of
sticking with Kalif,
John Morton Goff they talked about the
potential of Kalif St. and Jamo being a
trio um and their them forming a knit
bond, you know, going moving forward.
What How have you seen them, you know,
come together as a trio over the past
couple of weeks and what do you think
their potential could be? Well, I think
they uh look, everything in that room
starts with St., all right? And he he he
uh sets the standard in that room and
the temperature, right? And there's
things that are expected.
And uh and and then along the way those
guys have grown and Jamo's become one of
those guys for us, too, you know, those
are our veteran guys now, man, they do
it the right way um
and they take pride in their work and
and they're as happy as anybody to see
one of their guys score or make a play,
you know,
um
and now Kalif here we go, man, he's the
end of his his uh rookie year and to see
the growth, you know, that when you do
that, you begin to get trust, right? The
trust grows among your teammates, the
coaches, everybody. And so, um
you know,
I think ultimately you just want to feel
like some point that they feel like he's
he's he's one of theirs, right? You're
one of us and and that's where he's at
right now. Kalif's done that, I feel
like. Coach, that's the first time
facing D'Andre Swift, but you look at
him and how he's been productive this
season going against him. How have you
saw him grow and just seeing him game
planning against him this week as well,
like the impact he's had?
>> Yeah, it Well, we know Swift's
explosive. He's always been explosive.
Um
he he uh
he's he is consistently running hard,
right? You know, just man, he sees it,
he hits it and he goes and and time
after time after time, man, um
>> [snorts]
>> you just see um
a resilient runner, you know, I I I feel
like he he's got a good vision. They've
done a good job with the scheme for him
and uh
man, he's running through these tackles.
He's putting his foot in the ground,
going back and uh
and yeah, he he's he's running really
well, man. He's having a hell of a year.
Yeah, maybe it's not a a a perfect
measure, but there's been seven times
this season where you've been held under
100 rushing yards and you know, that's
that's been such a big part of your
identity is being able to run the
football. You're 0 and 7 in those games.
Yep. Um
when you say, you know, maybe we're not
that far away, we're we're close to to
getting to where we want to be next
year. How how
one critical is it to to get that going
and and maybe how daunting is it to
getting that back to to where it was?
It's everything.
I
uh Dan, one more Kalif question if I
can. How would you say that his
opportunity share has grown and taken
advantage of being um without Laporta
and Wright? Has that in the second half
of the season really opened him up to
more learning? That's helped, you know,
that that cuz he does get more
opportunities. Um
you know, we get in some of these games
where, you know, they
they start taking away St. and uh and
Jamo, you know, you get in some of these
criticals and they start getting doubled
and you know, that's why Leaf had a big
game Pittsburgh, you know, Leaf's one of
those guys, too, man, he he just keeps
going and going. Uh we got a good room.
It's a really good room.
Um but yes, those opportunities have
opened up because of that and and he's
made the most of them, you know, he has
and and there again, his trust uh
our trust in him has grown and and his
confidence has grown. He's just getting
better and better and better. How do you
expect to
How do you expect to call the game and
how much has your perspective changed
since maybe the end of 2021 as play
caller versus now with the offense
having grown and evolved since then?
Well, are you saying how do I expect to
call the game? This game?
>> Yeah, this kind of game, yeah. Um I'm
going to call it to win.
I'm going to call it to win. Um
but um
well, I think it's it's just it's it's a
little different. I mean, we, you know,
um [snorts]
we got some really good skill players,
you know, and uh trying to get those
guys the ball, you know, and finding
ways to to create ops for those I think
is the biggest thing, you know, that's
where it starts right now.
Clearly, you're playing to win, right?
You're playing most of your starters,
whatever it is. Penei, do you give any
update on his status and if he's not
able, could that impact how much or how
you use Goff? Uh the uh I don't see him
practicing today.
Um
and you know, this I don't know. I don't
know. I don't feel great about Sewell
right now. Um
but I'm always going to hold out hope.
Um
but as far as
um you know,
does it affect you not having Yeah, it
does. I mean, he he's a he's a
phenomenal player, you know, he's a
phenomenal football player. Yet, you
know, we got guys who are going to step
in and and uh do a good job for us, man.
They got a job to do. They'll have a
role and uh we expect them to to hold up
their end of the bargain. What caused
you to sit Goff though? I mean, not
having No.
Nope.
Dan.
>> [snorts]
[music]